Hester Lynch Piozzi Letters to Dr. William Makepeace Thackeray
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1807 February 17; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [34])
  Piozzi discusses the return of Mr. Piozzi's gout, which is now mending. She discusses the death of a lady as a "consequence of being quacked and magnetized" and wishes for medical reform. Piozzi also mentioned Mostyn's continued ill health, which she thinks might improve if he were less worried about it. Stocks are rising, and Piozzi predicts that Britain will soon control all of South America. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Dr. Parry, Mr. Bowen, Mr. Cam, Mrs. Siddons, "the prettiest lady we boasted at Bath," Mostyn, Mr. Tay[cut off] and Mrs. Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1807 December 1; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 20 cm. (Box [35])
  Piozzi discusses Sophia Thrale's marriage to Mr. Hoare and her own daughter's impending marriage to Admiral Lord Keith. Maria Dore has chest pains and is chlorotic and Piozzi discusses her treatment. People mentioned: Sophia Thrale, Mr. Hoare, Mrs. Piozzi's daughter, Admiral Lord Keith and Maria Dore {the undercook).
  Correspondence; Hoare, Henry Merrick, 1770-1856; Hoare, Sophia Thrale, 1771-1824; Elphinstone, George Keith, 1746-1823; Keith, Hester Maria Elphinstone, Viscountess, 1764-1857; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1807 December 31; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [36])
  Piozzi discusses Maria Dore's improving health. She asks Dr. Thackeray to send a servant to find out what happened to a valuable Gainsborough landscape she sent to her daughter as a bridal gift. She also comments on the war. People mentioned: Maria Dore, Sophia Hoare (Mrs. Piozzi's daughter), Gainsborough, Lord Keith and Buonaparte.
  Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 January 5; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 22 x 19 cm. (Box [37])
  Piozzi says that the landscape painting has been found. Mr. Piozzi is plagued with gout. Mrs. Piozzi hopes the Prince of Portugal will land safely and that Lord Strangford's health will improve. She also discusses the Queen's "sudden return to her senses." People mentioned: Mrs. Merrick Hoare, Mr. Piozzi, the Prince of Portugal, Lord Strangford, the "Old Queen" and Maria Dore.
  Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 January 17; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [38])
  Piozzi still worries about the fate of the landscape painting. The "brawn" she ordered to cure Mr. Piozzi's itching has been lost on the road. Piozzi also remarks on the growing local population. People mentioned: Sophia Hoare, Barclay, Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, Mr. Rogers and Lady Keith.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 March 23; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [40])
  Mr. Piozzi continues to complain of gout. Mrs. Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray to choose and send winter trees for her. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, "General Lake" (a servant) and Mrs. Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 "Lady Day"; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 15 x 19 cm. (Box [41])
  Mr. Piozzi is still ill, but was able to sign a checque repaying Dr. Thackeray for the trees, which Mrs. Piozzi finds comforting. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 April 13; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [42])
  Piozzi complains that the people who sent the trees treated them poorly, but she thanks Dr. Thackeray for his trouble. Mr. Piozzi is in somewhat better health, but wants soda water for his thirst. Mrs. Piozzi thanks Dr. Thackeray for saying she looked younger than her "lovely Contemporary Lady Crewe." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Lady Crewe.
  Correspondence; Crewe, Frances Anne, 1748-1818; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 June 29; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 19 cm. (Box [43])
  Piozzi discusses the gout that is all over Mr. Piozzi, and the sickness of all the servants. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, Selina, Selina's uncle, Mr. Jackson and Jonathan.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 July 4; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [44])
  Everyone is ill, and Mr. Piozzi's gout is "shocking." The laborer Harry Hughes was injured in a fall and Mrs. Piozzi is waiting for some wine to arrive. People mentioned: "Poor Richard," Mr. Piozzi, Harry Hughes, Mr. Jackson, Captain Jones, Mr. William Field and Mr. Stroud.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 August 29; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 20 cm. (Box [45])
  Piozzi discusses Mr. Piozzi's improved health. The Hoare's are visiting, including Sir Richard Hoare, an antiquarian, who is interested in "some curious Coins" (probably Roman) dug up in the area within the last few decades. Mrs. Piozzi is trying to discover what became of them. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Merrick Hoare, Mrs. Merrick Hoare, Sir Richard Hoare, Mr. Crane, Vicar Mr. Roberts, Miss Selina, Mrs. Thackeray and Mrs. Thackeray's brother.
  Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809; Hoare, Richard Colt, Sir, 1758-1838
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 September 6; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 3 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [46])
  Piozzi writes that Mr. Piozzi's health suddenly worsened soon after her last letter. She herself suffers from bad nerves, but is consoled by the accounts of military victory that "strike some fire" in Mr. Piozzi's eyes. People mentioned: Mr. Crane, Mr. Piozzi, Selina and Mr. Broster.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 November 19; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [47])
  Piozzi's maid Chauncey requests some of Dr. Thackeray's "Electuary," which Mr. Moore cannot make because he has no Roman Wormwood. Piozzi hopes Napoleon's difficulties in Spain, even if he conquers it, will show that he has more "good Fortune" than "good Conduct," and prove that he is an "Empiric rather than a great General or Politician." Mr. Piozzi is cross, but on the whole in much better health. People mentioned: Chauncey, Mr. Moore, Mr. Broster, Lady Williams, Buonaparte, Miss Selina and Thackeray's brother.
  Correspondence; Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1808 December 14; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [48])
  Piozzi complains that she cannot find the source of a line of poetry, though she believes it may be from Young's Night Thoughts. She details Mr. Piozzi's ill health and the dismal news of Napoleon's triumphs in Spain. She doubts the veracity of tales of monsters in Bell's Evening Messenger, believing they are written with the express intention of frightening "Readers of a particular Class." An "Address to Brother Soldiers and Countrymen" is also circulating. People mentioned: Young, Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Robson, Bishop Hoarsley, Mrs. Thackeray. Selina, Mrs. Newton, Mr. Crane, William Spencer and Chauncey.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 January 18; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [49])
  Mr. Piozzi's health worsens. Mrs. Piozzi discusses the threat of Irish rebellion and the "perverse" behavior of the "old King." She enquires after Dr. Thackeray's sister Kilfenora. Mr. Moore says that some of Mr. Piozzi's symptoms are "merely nervous" and don't pose any danger, but Mrs. Piozzi's doubts him, saying Mr. Moore "says some same of the State." People mentioned: Mr. Moore, Mr. Piozzi, the King, Kilfenora and Selina.
  Medicine -- Great Britain; Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 February 2; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 3 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [50a])
  Piozzi begs Dr. Thackeray to come. Mr. Piozzi is vomiting and feverish. Mr. Moore continues the letter on the verso in [50b]. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 February 3; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [50b])
  On the verso of [50a], Mr. Moore writes that he left Mr. Piozzi "considerably better," but is still desirous of Dr. Thackeray's advice. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 February 17; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [51])
  Mr. Piozzi has improved after Dr. Thackeray's visit and has been taking opiates to combat symptoms. Mrs. Piozzi fears he "is now doomed & destined to take some Narcotic Medicine for the remainder of this Year 1809." However, the opiates allow Mr. Piozzi to consume less brandy. Surprisingly, even Mr. Piozzi agrees that he is feeling better. Life is dull, and Mrs. Piozzi wonders if it is safe for Mr. Piozzi to drink beer. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mrs. Clarke, Mrs. Mostyn, Salusbury and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 February 26; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (4 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [52])
  Mr. Piozzi is ill again and woke one night "in something like a delirious Fury." Mr. Piozzi raves, but Mrs. Piozzi hopes that rest will help him, and says that as long as she keeps her "own Wits," she would not change "with the King or Duke of York." She also comments on current affairs and writes that some of the tales of monsters are indeed true. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, the King, the Duke of York, Mr. Robson of Chirk, Mrs. Yorke, the Emperor of China, "some Fasting Woman" and Cecilia Mostyn.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 February 28; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [53])
  Piozzi writes that sleep cured her husband's deliriums, but his gout is still painful. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 March 5; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [54])
  Piozzi writes, "my poor husband lives here in a World of his own creating," and begs Dr. Thackeray to come. She thinks wine and brandy are inflaming Mr. Piozzi's back. Mrs. Piozzi also asks Dr. Thackeray to bring some pens, saying, "I wrote this with some bad Imitation of a Skewer." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore and Dunscombe (Mr. Piozzi's man).
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [55])
  Piozzi discusses Mr. Piozzi's health, writing that, while his delirium is gone, his "ulcer exhibits a Hole in which you may bury a small Phial" and Mr. Moore refuses to consider the possibility of gangrene. Mr. Piozzi suffers from the cold and a variety of other painful symptoms, and Mrs. Piozzi herself is ill with nerves. She does not approve of Mr. Moore's diagnoses. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, Dunscombe and Mr. Heaton.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [56a])
  Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray if she should use "Bark" to stop the gangrene around Mr. Piozzi's coccyx. Mr. Piozzi has been covered with chalk to prevent putrefaction and his delirium has disappeared. Mr. Moore continues the letter on the verso: [56b]. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [56b])
  Mr. Moore continues the letter Mrs. Piozzi began in [56a]. Mr. Moore details Mr. Piozzi's symptoms, which include discharges, and also discusses the departure of Mr. Piozzi's delirium and the use of "Blisters." People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Dunscombe.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 March 19; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [57])
  Mrs. Piozzi and Mr. Moore both write notes on the same page asking Dr. Thackeray to come. "Mr. Piozzi is ulcerated from Head to Foot." People mentioned: Mr. Moore and Mr. Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 March 22; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [58])
  Piozzi writes that Mr. Piozzi feels much better, but does not seem "quite himself" and does not remember Dr. Thackeray's recent visit. With Mr. Piozzi's consent, Mrs. Piozzi has sent for Salusbury, though she thinks Mr. Piozzi "will live till the Summer Holdydays". Mr. Piozzi's wound is spreading and Mrs. Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray if there is any hope. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Moore, Salusbury, Jones, Mr. Charles Shepherd and "the Child".
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 March 24?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [59])
  Mrs. Piozzi complains that Mr. Moore insists on dressing Mr. Piozzi's wounds, a torturous process, even though Mr. Piozzi is unlikely to live three more days. People mentioned: Mr. Piozzi and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [60])
  It appears that the first two paragraphs of the letter may be written by Mrs. Piozzi, but the remainder and certainly the verso are written by Mr. Moore. Mr. Piozzi has passed away. People mentioned: "the Ladies," "the Boy," Mr. Piozzi, Mr. Jones, Mrs. Piozzi and Mrs. Mostyn.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 April 7; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [61])
  Piozzi passes on regards from her nephew Salusbury, who will attend Christ Church, Oxford, and his friend Mr. Shephard, who attended Eton. Both young men have helped Mrs. Piozzi in her grief. People mentioned: Salusbury, Mr. Shephard, Mr. Shephard's father and Jackson's [?].
  Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, John Salusbury
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 April 8?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 20 cm. (Box [62])
  Piozzi plans to travel to London to visit her daughters. Piozzi still grieves for her husband, but has received some comfort from Salusbury settling her "future concerns". She plans to stay at Jackson's Hotel in London because she "cannot bear either Society or Solitude" and she quotes a newspaper paragraph about her husband's burial. People mentioned: Piozzi's daughters, Salusbury, William Shephard, Mrs. Thackeray, Selina Thackeray and Gabriel Piozzi.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 April 13; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [63])
  Piozzi requests Dr. Thackeray's help in transporting her late husband's piano to Lady Keith. She also details symptoms she is suffering, which she attributes to nerves. She looks forward to dining soon with Dr. Thackeray. People mentioned: Lady Keith, Mr. Piozzi, Lake, Mr. Moore, Selina Thackeray and Selina's mother (Mrs. Thackeray).
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 April 26; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [64])
  Piozzi writes that she has arrived in London, but suffered from bad nerves along the road. She discusses political and social news concerning the nobility and complains that she left spring behind "in North Wales." People mentioned: Selina Thackeray, Lord Dundonald, Lord Cochrane, Mr. Wandle, Sir Lucas Pepys, Lady Caroline Paget, Lady William Russell and Lady Jersey.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1809 July 23; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 25 x 20 cm. (Box [65])
  Piozzi discusses mutual friends and quotes Dr. Johnson. People mentioned: Sir Lucas Pepys, Mrs. Mostyn, Mrs. Mostyn's three sons, Dr. Myddleton, the Dean of St. Asaph, Mr. Moore, Mrs. Clarke, Dr. Johnson, Salusbury, Mr. Thrale, "The Ladies" (Mr. Thrale's daughters), farmer Jones and farmer Jones's wife.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 March 27; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [66])
  Written from Bath. Piozzi discusses spelling, various gossip, Lord Byron's popular satires, and current affairs, "which scarcely can be mended by the wisest, though they may be made worse by unskillful Touches". People mentioned: Mrs. Thackeray, Salusbury, Dr. Hall (Dean of Christ Church), Lord Byron, Miss Holford, Wallace, and Selina Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 July 4; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 3 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [67])
  Piozzi requests Dr. Thackeray's advice in choosing a horse for Salusbury--"something safe for my sake, and something showy for his." She discusses the dry weather and the political situation and laments Sir Lucas Pepys' loss of his Countess, "a companion of uncommon Power of Mind,--& 800 Pounds a Year." People mentioned: Piozzi's steward, Salusbury, Selina Thackeray, Dr. Thackeray's brother, Sir Francis Burdett, Sir Lucas Pepys and Countess (Pepys' former wife).
  Correspondence; Horses; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Pepys, Lucas, Sir, 1742-1830
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 July 10; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 25 x 20 cm. (Box [68])
  Piozzi discusses Ann Moore ("the fasting woman of Tutburry"). Piozzi's health has improved, and her "heart--as it is Empty--has Pretentions to be light." Rain has finally come, quieting "Fears of Famine", but the farmer Jones and his family still suffer from poor health. Piozzi also mentions the biting "Edinburgh Reviewers" and Kingston's "Vindication of Oxford University." People mentioned: Anne Moore, Mrs. Mostyn, Farmer Jones of Pontriffeth, Mr. Moore, Miss Allen, Mrs. Heaton, Miss Ashburne, Selina Thackeray, Kingston and Lady Keith.
  Correspondence; Moore, Ann, b. 1761; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 August 1; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [69])
  Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray to check on the safety of some valuable china jars she sent to Paddington Wharf in London. She sent some of Mr. Hall's poetry to Lady Keith and wonders what her response will be. People mentioned: Mr. Moore, Lady Keith, Mr. Hall, Empress Louisa, Mrs. Mostyn, Salusbury, Pemberton, Smith Owen and Selina Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 August 16; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [70])
  Piozzi writes that "Mr. Hall's Book shall have all the help I can give it" and asks to be send two more copies. She also orders a new edition of Brandt's Popular Superstitions and the Romance of Sr. Leon. People mentioned: Mr. Hall, Mr. Broster, Brandt and Selina Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 September 7; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 4 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [71])
  Piozzi discusses news about family and friends and Anne Moore "the starving woman," writing, "this has been a famous year for monsters--human ones I mean". The china has finally arrived. People mentioned: Mrs. Gittins, Rees, Sir Stephen Glynn, Martin (Dr. Thackeray's brother), Mr. Moore, Salusbury, Pemberton of Condover, Mrs. Heaton, Miss Margaret and Anne Moore.
  Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence; Moore, Ann, b. 1761; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1810 December?; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [72])
  Piozzi writes that her health is improved but still tenuous. She worries about the bankruptcy of one of her tenants. People mentioned: Mr. Morhall.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1811 May 27; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 1 page (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm. (Box [73])
  Piozzi asks Dr. Thackeray to check on a box of china ware sent from Bond Street "by the Chester Wagon" and mentions her son's recent graduation from Oxford. People mentioned: Piozzi's son, Mrs. Thackeray, and Mr. Moore.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1811 October 5; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [74])
  Piozzi relates how her dairy maid went mad two years ago and was taken with money and good clothes to an asylum. She has returned to Piozzi's parish a pauper and Piozzi wishes to help her, perhaps by sending her to an asylum in Liverpool. People mentioned: William Chappelow, Piozzi's dairy maid, and the dairy maid's brothers.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1811 December 24; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm. (Box [75])
  Discusses the end of the year and looks forward to Salusbury's visit to Dr. Thackeray. People mentioned: Salusbury, Mrs. Thackeray, and Selina Thackeray.
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1812 May 30; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 3 pages (2 leaves): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 19 cm. (Box [76])
  Asks Dr. Thackeray to ensure that a "transparency for the Bow window at old Bachygraig" reaches its destination safely. Piozzi's daughters are angry at her for cutting down some timber at Streatham Park for use in repairs. People mentioned: Salusbury, Leak (the steward), William Charles Shepherd, Mead (the surveyor), Mrs. Mostyn, Mrs. Thackeray, and Miss Barnstone.
  Correspondence; Streatham Park (London, England); Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863 -- Correspondence; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821 -- Correspondence
- Letter to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1812 November 24; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed; 22 x 18 cm. (Box [77])